CHRIS OLIVER

40 N Kingshighway Blvd Apt 4A, St. Louis, MO 63108 chris@excid3.com | Phone: +12174080040 excid3.com | github.com/excid3

SKILLS

Web development and user experience architect experienced in web technologies including Ruby on Rails, Django, HTML, CSS, XML, JSON, SQL, and Javascript to build and design interactive web applications. Proficient with Ruby, Python, version control including Git, Bazaar, Subversion, and Mercurial and the GTK and wxWidgets UI toolkits.

EXPERIENCE

Ruby on Rails Developer

June 2012 - Present

Consultant - St. Louis, MO

- Building and maintaining projects for multiple clients, organizations, and businesses
- Responsible for software development, deployment, and server set up and maintenance

Rails Developer

August 2011 – June 2012

The Able Few - St. Louis, MO

 Lead Ruby on Rails developer for many client projects with responsibilities including working with clients and designers directly to implement projects in Ruby on Rails

Programmer Analyst

June 2011 – August 2011

The Genome Institute - St. Louis, MO

- Worked with cancer researchers and software developers to document and dynamically generate documentation websites for the purpose of fund raising
- Provided software support and maintenance for tools being used by cancer researchers

Web Developer

July 2010 - May 2011

Zooniverse - Edwardsville, IL

- Maintaining and adding features to production websites running in Ruby on Rails.
- Working with developers both locally and remotely using Capistrano and Amazon web services (EC2 and S3) to deploy web applications.

Founder & Lead Developer

May 2008 – Present

Keryx Project - keryxproject.org - Jacksonville, IL

- Designed and implemented a desktop software package for computers without internet access to download software for Ubuntu Linux.
- Developed with a small, distributed team using Python, wxWidgets, and GTK technologies
- Shipped and supported over 150,000 copies used in third world countries, governments, and other systems with poor internet connections.

Summer of Code Software Engineer

May 2009 – September 2009

Google, Inc. – Jacksonville, IL

- Accepted as one of 1000 students world-wide into Google Summer of Code.
- Served as a developer on the WinLibre open source project team.
- Designed and implemented a software package system for Windows using Python.

PUBLICATIONS

Offline Package Installation. Full Circle Magazine. December 2009: Issue 32. Pp. 14-16. fullcirclemagazine.org.

EDUCATION

Southern Illinois University – Edwardsville

Expected May 2011

B.S. Computer Science